PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DAJ	Kraufvelin, P; Pekcan-Hekim, Z; Bergstrom, U; Florin, AB; Lehikoinen, A; Mattila, J; Arula, T; Briekmane, L; Brown, EJ; Celmer, Z; Dainys, J; Jokinen, H; Kaaria, P; Kallasvuo, M; Lappalainen, A; Lozys, L; Moller, P; Orio, A; Rohtla, M; Saks, L; Snickars, M; Stottrup, J; Sundblad, G; Taal, I; Ustups, D; Verliin, A; Vetemaa, M; Winkler, H; Wozniczka, A; Olsson, J				Kraufvelin, Patrik; Pekcan-Hekim, Zeynep; Bergstrom, Ulf; Florin, Ann-Britt; Lehikoinen, Annukka; Mattila, Johanna; Arula, Timo; Briekmane, Laura; Brown, Elliot John; Celmer, Zuzanna; Dainys, Justas; Jokinen, Henri; Kaaria, Petra; Kallasvuo, Men; Lappalainen, Antti; Lozys, Linas; Moeller, Peter; Orio, Alessandro; Rohtla, Mehis; Saks, Lauri; Snickars, Martin; Stottrup, Josianne; Sundblad, Goran; Taal, Imre; Ustups, Didzis; Verliin, Aare; Vetemaa, Markus; Winkler, Helmut; Wozniczka, Adam; Olsson, Jens			Essential coastal habitats for fish in the Baltic Sea	ESTUARINE COASTAL AND SHELF SCIENCE			English	Review							GOBY NEOGOBIUS-MELANOSTOMUS; LONG-TERM CHANGES; PIKE ESOX-LUCIUS; FLOUNDER PLATICHTHYS-FLESUS; ROACH RUTILUS-RUTILUS; SWEDISH WEST-COAST; RHITHROPANOPEUS-HARRISII GOULD; SPECIES DISTRIBUTION MODELS; ECOSYSTEM-BASED MANAGEMENT; INDIGENOUS ROUND GOBY	Many coastal and offshore fish species are highly dependent on specific habitat types for population maintenance. In the Baltic Sea, shallow productive habitats in the coastal zone such as wetlands, vegetated flads/lagoons and sheltered bays as well as more exposed rocky and sandy areas are utilized by fish across many life history stages including spawning, juvenile development, feeding and migration. Although there is general consensus about the critical importance of these essential fish habitats (EFH) for fish production along the coast, direct quantitative evidence for their specific roles in population growth and maintenance is still scarce. Nevertheless, for some coastal species, indirect evidence exists, and in many cases, sufficient data are also available to carry out further quantitative analyses. As coastal EFH in the Baltic Sea are often found in areas that are highly utilized and valued by humans, they are subjected to many different pressures. While cumulative pressures, such as eutrophication, coastal construction and development, climate change, invasive species and fisheries, impact fish in coastal areas, the conservation coverage for EFH in these areas remains poor. This is mainly due to the fact that historically, fisheries management and nature conservation are not integrated neither in research nor in management in Baltic Sea countries. Setting joint objectives for fisheries management and nature conservation would hence be pivotal for improved protection of EFH in the Baltic Sea. To properly inform management, improvements in the development of monitoring strategies and mapping methodology for EFH are also needed. Stronger international cooperation between Baltic Sea states will facilitate improved management outcomes across ecologically arbitrary boundaries. This is especially important for successful implementation of international agreements and legislative directives such as the Baltic Sea Action Plan, the Marine Strategy Framework Directive, the Habitats Directive, and the Maritime Spatial Planning Directive, but also for improving the communication of information related to coastal EFH among researchers, stakeholders, managers and decision makers. In this paper, efforts are made to characterize coastal EFH in the Baltic Sea, their importance and the threats/pressures they face, as well as their current conservation status, while highlighting knowledge gaps and outlining perspectives for future work in an ecosystem-based management framework. (C) 2018 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.	[Kraufvelin, Patrik; Pekcan-Hekim, Zeynep; Bergstrom, Ulf; Florin, Ann-Britt; Lehikoinen, Annukka; Mattila, Johanna; Olsson, Jens] Swedish Univ Agr Sci, Inst Coastal Res, Dept Aquat Resources, Skolgatan 6, S-74242 Oregrund, Sweden; [Kraufvelin, Patrik; Mattila, Johanna; Snickars, Martin] Abo Akad Univ, Environm & Marine Biol, Turku, Finland; [Lehikoinen, Annukka] Univ Helsinki, Kotka Maritime Res Ctr, Kotka, Finland; [Arula, Timo; Rohtla, Mehis; Saks, Lauri; Taal, Imre; Verliin, Aare; Vetemaa, Markus] Univ Tartu, Estonian Marine Inst, Tartu, Estonia; [Briekmane, Laura; Ustups, Didzis] Inst Food Safety Anim Hlth & Environm BIOR, Riga, Latvia; [Brown, Elliot John; Stottrup, Josianne] Tech Univ Denmark, Natl Inst Aquat Resources, DTU Aqua, Lyngby, Denmark; [Celmer, Zuzanna; Wozniczka, Adam] Natl Marine Fisheries Res Inst, Gdynia, Poland; [Dainys, Justas; Lozys, Linas] Nat Res Ctr, Vilnius, Lithuania; [Jokinen, Henri] Univ Helsinki, Tvarminne Zool Stn, Hango, Finland; [Kaaria, Petra] HELCOM Secretariat, Helsinki, Finland; [Kallasvuo, Men; Lappalainen, Antti] Nat Resources Inst Finland Luke, Helsinki, Finland; [Moeller, Peter] Mecklenburg Vorpommern, Fisch & Umwelt, Rostock, Germany; [Orio, Alessandro] Swedish Univ Agr Sci, Inst Marine Res, Dept Aquat Resources, Lysekil, Sweden; [Sundblad, Goran] AquaBiota Water Res, Stockholm, Sweden; [Sundblad, Goran] Swedish Univ Agr Sci, Inst Freshwater Res, Dept Aquat Resources, Drottningholm, Sweden; [Winkler, Helmut] Univ Rostock, Rostock, Germany	Kraufvelin, P (reprint author), Swedish Univ Agr Sci, Inst Coastal Res, Dept Aquat Resources, Skolgatan 6, S-74242 Oregrund, Sweden.	patrik.kraufvelin@slu.se		Orio, Alessandro/0000-0002-5566-6139; Jokinen, Henri/0000-0001-7617-7820; Florin, Ann-Britt/0000-0002-7531-2231; Wozniczka, Adam/0000-0001-5050-9145; Sundblad, Goran/0000-0001-8970-9996	Nordic Council of Ministers [14328]	The workshop and preparation of the review article was funded by the Nordic Council of Ministers, for the project 14328 "Betydelsen av kustnara essentiella habitat for fisk i Ostersjon - kunskapslage, kartlaggning och overvakning" to Jens Olsson at Swedish University of Agricultural Sciences.		228	0	0	33	33	ACADEMIC PRESS LTD- ELSEVIER SCIENCE LTD	LONDON	24-28 OVAL RD, LONDON NW1 7DX, ENGLAND	0272-7714	1096-0015		ESTUAR COAST SHELF S	Estuar. Coast. Shelf Sci.	MAY 1	2018	204						14	30		10.1016/j.ecss.2018.02.014				17	Marine & Freshwater Biology; Oceanography	Marine & Freshwater Biology; Oceanography	GC4LZ	WOS:000429757300002					2018-10-25	J	Schmera, D; Podani, J; Botta-Dukat, Z; Eros, T				Schmera, Denes; Podani, Janos; Botta-Dukat, Zoltan; Eros, Tibor			On the reliability of the Elements of Metacommunity Structure framework for separating idealized metacommunity patterns	ECOLOGICAL INDICATORS			English	Article						Biodiversity; Community pattern; Pattern analysis; Idealized metacommunity patterns	NULL MODEL ANALYSIS; COMPREHENSIVE FRAMEWORK; NESTEDNESS ANALYSIS; COMMUNITY ECOLOGY; BETA DIVERSITY; ENVIRONMENT; TURNOVER; MEANINGS	The Elements of Metacommunity Structure (EMS) framework originally suggested by Leibold and Mikkelson (2002) in Oikos is a popular approach to identify idealized metacommunity patterns (i.e. checkerboard, nested, evenly spaced, Clementsian, Gleasonian), and hereby to infer the existence of structuring processes in meta communities. Essentially, the EMS framework consists of the rearrangement of the sites-by-species incidence matrix followed by a series of tests for coherence, turnover and boundary clumping in species distributions. Here, we give a critical evaluation of the EMS framework based on theoretical considerations and simulations. We found that user defined site ordering may influence the coherence test (number of embedded absences) depending also on the ordering of species, and therefore we argue that the application of user-defined matrix rearrangement has strong limitations. The recommended ordering by correspondence analysis is sensitive to matrix structure and may even include arbitrary decisions in special cases. Further, we revealed different meanings of the checkerboard pattern and showed that negative coherence is not necessarily associated with this as assumed in the EMS framework. Also, the turnover test cannot always detect nested pattern, because turnover and nestedness are not necessarily the opposite endpoints of a continuum. We argue that the boundary clumping test can only be used for separating Clementsian, Gleasonian and evenly spaced patterns if sites are ordered along a real environmental gradient rather than a latent one identified by correspondence analysis. We found that the series of tests in the EMS framework are burdened by anomalies and that the detection of some metacommunity patterns is sensitive to type II error. In sum, our findings suggest that the analytical methodology of the EMS framework, as well as the conclusions drawn from its application to metacommunity studies require careful reconsideration.	[Schmera, Denes; Eros, Tibor] MTA Ctr Ecol Res, Balaton Limnol Inst, Klebelsberg K U 3, H-8392 Tihany, Hungary; [Schmera, Denes; Botta-Dukat, Zoltan; Eros, Tibor] MTA Ctr Ecol Res, GINOP Sustainable Ecosyst Grp, Klebelsberg K U 3, H-8392 Tihany, Hungary; [Podani, Janos] Eotvos Lorand Univ, Inst Biol, Dept Plant Systemat Ecol & Theoret Biol, Pazmany Ps 1-C, H-1117 Budapest, Hungary; [Podani, Janos] Hungarian Acad Sci, Ecol Res Grp, Budapest, Hungary; [Botta-Dukat, Zoltan] MTA Ctr Ecol Res, Inst Ecol & Bot, Alkotmany U 2-4, H-2163 Vacratot, Hungary	Schmera, D (reprint author), MTA Ctr Ecol Res, Balaton Limnol Inst, Klebelsberg K U 3, H-8392 Tihany, Hungary.	schmera.denes@okologia.mta.hu			OTKA [K104279]; GINOP [2.3.3-15-2016-00019]	This work was supported by the OTKA K104279 and the GINOP 2.3.3-15-2016-00019 grants.		41	0	0	6	6	ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV	AMSTERDAM	PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS	1470-160X	1872-7034		ECOL INDIC	Ecol. Indic.	FEB	2018	85						853	860		10.1016/j.ecolind.2017.31.022				8	Biodiversity Conservation; Environmental Sciences	Biodiversity & Conservation; Environmental Sciences & Ecology	GD6QW	WOS:000430634500084					2018-10-25	J	Moudry, V; Komarek, J; Simova, P				Moudry, Vitezslav; Komarek, Jan; Simova, Petra			Which breeding bird categories should we use in models of species distribution?	ECOLOGICAL INDICATORS			English	Article						Ambiguity; Atlas; Calibration; Species distribution model; Validation; Wetland birds	SAMPLE-SIZE; CLIMATE; AREAS; UNCERTAINTY; PREDICTIONS; ACCURACY; SCALE; NEED	Studies often use breeding bird atlases to assess species' habitat requirements or to estimate species' potential distribution under environmental changes. In breeding bird atlases, one of the attributes recorded for each grid square is evidence of breeding. The attribute represent probability of breeding (confirmed, probable, possible) categorized according to breeding behaviour. However, the majority of studies often make arbitrary decisions on which category to use. This may have severe consequences for results. This study evaluated whether models' discrimination ability change by inclusion of ambiguous breeding categories (probable, possible). We compared models' predictions for distribution of nine wetland birds derived from Atlas of the breeding distribution of birds in the Czech Republic. For each species, we developed generalized linear models using combinations of the breeding categories as input to model calibration and validation. Our results show that the discrimination ability (AUC) decreased in most cases when all breeding categories were uncritically used in calibration and validation process. On the other hand, however, inclusion of probable and possible breeding categories to model calibration did not affect models' abilities to predict confirmed presences and absences. This implies that inclusion of ambiguous breeding categories has more serious impact on models' performance when added to validation than to calibration data set. We advocate for more rigorous use of different breeding categories and emphasize that widely used atlases from citizen science programmes offer more than simple occurrence data. Additional attributes (e.g. breeding category, sampling effort) should be used to select high quality data to validate the models. (C) 2016 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.	[Moudry, Vitezslav; Komarek, Jan; Simova, Petra] Czech Univ Life Sci Prague, Fac Environm Sci, Dept Appl Geoinformat & Spatial Planning, Kamycka 129, Prague 16521 6, Czech Republic	Moudry, V (reprint author), Czech Univ Life Sci Prague, Fac Environm Sci, Dept Appl Geoinformat & Spatial Planning, Kamycka 129, Prague 16521 6, Czech Republic.	moudry@fzp.czu.cz	Komarek, Jan/N-4898-2018	Komarek, Jan/0000-0002-3505-6755	Czech University of Life Sciences, Prague [20154209]	This work was supported by the Czech University of Life Sciences, Prague [grant number 20154209]. We are very grateful to Simon Gillings and two anonymous referees who provided helpful reviews on the original manuscript.		32	2	2	2	15	ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV	AMSTERDAM	PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS	1470-160X	1872-7034		ECOL INDIC	Ecol. Indic.	MAR	2017	74						526	529		10.1016/j.ecolind.2016.11.006				4	Biodiversity Conservation; Environmental Sciences	Biodiversity & Conservation; Environmental Sciences & Ecology	EQ8KO	WOS:000398334500047					2018-10-25	J	Petrov, AN; Wessling, JM				Petrov, Andrey N.; Wessling, Jordan M.			Utilization of machine-learning algorithms for wind turbine site suitability modeling in Iowa, USA	WIND ENERGY			English	Article						wind energy; turbine site suitability; machine-learning; multicriteria decision making; spatial modeling	DECISION-SUPPORT-SYSTEM; GIS-BASED APPROACH; GEOGRAPHIC DISTRIBUTIONS; SPECIES DISTRIBUTIONS; VISUAL IMPACT; ENERGY; FARMS; PREDICTION; CHINA; SCALE	Because of the current shift away from fossil fuels and toward renewable energy sources, it is necessary to plan for the installation of new infrastructure to meet the demand for clean energy. Traditional methods for determining wind turbine site suitability suffer from the selection of arbitrary criteria and model parameters by experts, which may lead to a degree of uncertainty in the models produced. An alternative empirically based methodology for building a wind turbine siting model for the state of Iowa is presented in the study. We employ ecological niche' principles traditionally utilized to model species allocation to develop a new multicriteria, spatially explicit framework for wind turbine placement. Using information on suitability conditions at existing turbine locations, we incorporate seven variables (wind speed, elevation, slope, land cover, distance of infrastructure and settlements, and population density) into two machine-learning algorithms [maximum entropy method (Maxent) and Genetic Algorithm for Rule Set Prediction (GARP)] to model suitable areas for installation of wind turbines. The performance of this method is tested at the statewide level and a six-county region in western Iowa. Maxent and GARP identified areas in the Northwest and North Central regions of Iowa as the optimum location for new wind turbines. Information on variable contributions from Maxent illuminates the relative importance of environmental variables and its scale-dependent nature. It also allows validating existing assumptions about the relationship between variables and wind turbine suitability. The resultant models demonstrate high levels of accuracy and suggest that the presented approach is a possible methodology for developing wind turbine siting applications. Copyright (c) 2014 John Wiley & Sons, Ltd.	[Petrov, Andrey N.; Wessling, Jordan M.] Univ No Iowa, Cedar Falls, IA 50614 USA	Petrov, AN (reprint author), Univ No Iowa, Cedar Falls, IA 50614 USA.	andrey.petrov@uni.edu			National Science Foundation [EPS-1101284]	This work was supported by the National Science Foundation under grant no. EPS-1101284.		49	2	2	1	21	WILEY-BLACKWELL	HOBOKEN	111 RIVER ST, HOBOKEN 07030-5774, NJ USA	1095-4244	1099-1824		WIND ENERGY	Wind Energy	APR	2015	18	4					713	727		10.1002/we.1723				15	Energy & Fuels; Engineering, Mechanical	Energy & Fuels; Engineering	CD6BC	WOS:000351172400009					2018-10-25	J	Braunisch, V; Coppes, J; Arlettaz, R; Suchant, R; Schmid, H; Bollmann, K				Braunisch, Veronika; Coppes, Joy; Arlettaz, Raphael; Suchant, Rudi; Schmid, Hans; Bollmann, Kurt			Selecting from correlated climate variables: a major source of uncertainty for predicting species distributions under climate change	ECOGRAPHY			English	Article							CAPERCAILLIE TETRAO-UROGALLUS; DISTRIBUTION MODELS; RANGE SHIFTS; HABITAT SUITABILITY; BIOTIC INTERACTIONS; IMPROVE PREDICTION; CONSERVATION; IMPACTS; FUTURE; NICHE	Correlative species distribution models are frequently used to predict species' range shifts under climate change. However, climate variables often show high collinearity and most statistical approaches require the selection of one among strongly correlated variables. When causal relationships between species presence and climate parameters are unknown, variable selection is often arbitrary, or based on predictive performance under current conditions. While this should only marginally affect current range predictions, future distributions may vary considerably when climate parameters do not change in concert. We investigated this source of uncertainty using four highly correlated climate variables together with a constant set of landscape variables in order to predict current (2010) and future (2050) distributions of four mountain bird species in central Europe. Simulating different parameterization decisions, we generated a) four models including each of the climate variables singly, b) a model taking advantage of all variables simultaneously and c) an un-weighted average of the predictions of a). We compared model accuracy under current conditions, predicted distributions under four scenarios of climate change, and - for one species - evaluated back-projections using historical occurrence data. Although current and future variable-correlations remained constant, and the models' accuracy under contemporary conditions did not differ, future range predictions varied considerably in all climate change scenarios. Averaged models and models containing all climate variables simultaneously produced intermediate predictions; the latter, however, performed best in back-projections. This pattern, consistent across different modelling methods, indicates a benefit from including multiple climate predictors in ambiguous situations. Variable selection proved to be an important source of uncertainty for future range predictions, difficult to control using contemporary information. Small, but diverging changes of climate variables, masked by constant overall correlation patterns, can cause substantial differences between future range predictions which need to be accounted for, particularly when outcomes are intended for conservation decisions.	[Braunisch, Veronika; Arlettaz, Raphael] Univ Bern, Inst Ecol & Evolut, CH-3012 Bern, Switzerland; [Braunisch, Veronika; Coppes, Joy; Suchant, Rudi] Forest Res Inst Baden Wurttemberg FVA, DE-79100 Freiburg, Germany; [Arlettaz, Raphael] Swiss Ornithol Inst, Valais Field Stn, CH-1950 Sion, Switzerland; [Schmid, Hans] Swiss Ornithol Inst, CH-6204 Sempach, Switzerland; [Bollmann, Kurt] Swiss Fed Inst Forest Snow & Landscape Res WSL, CH-8903 Birmensdorf, Switzerland	Braunisch, V (reprint author), Univ Bern, Inst Ecol & Evolut, Baltzerstr 6, CH-3012 Bern, Switzerland.	veronika.braunisch@iee.unibe.ch	Arlettaz, Raphael/O-2182-2016	Arlettaz, Raphael/0000-0001-6360-5339	Baden-Wurttemberg Fund for Environmental Research; research programme 'Forest and climate change' of the Swiss Federal Inst. for Forest, Snow and Landscape Research WSL; Federal Office for the Environment FOEN	We thank Niklaus Zimmermann and Achilleas Psomas for providing the climate data, Sebastien Nussle for valuable comments on the statistics and Aliki Buhayer for language editing. The work was funded by the Baden-Wurttemberg Fund for Environmental Research, and by the research programme 'Forest and climate change' of the Swiss Federal Inst. for Forest, Snow and Landscape Research WSL and the Federal Office for the Environment FOEN.		85	70	72	3	96	WILEY	HOBOKEN	111 RIVER ST, HOBOKEN 07030-5774, NJ USA	0906-7590	1600-0587		ECOGRAPHY	Ecography	SEP	2013	36	9					971	983		10.1111/j.1600-0587.2013.00138.x				13	Biodiversity Conservation; Ecology	Biodiversity & Conservation; Environmental Sciences & Ecology	208SZ	WOS:000323701100004					2018-10-25	J	Regan, TJ; Taylor, BL; Thompson, GG; Cochrane, JF; Ralls, K; Runge, MC; Merrick, R				Regan, Tracey J.; Taylor, Barbara L.; Thompson, Grant G.; Cochrane, Jean Fitts; Ralls, Katherine; Runge, Michael C.; Merrick, Richard			Testing Decision Rules for Categorizing Species' Extinction Risk to Help Develop Quantitative Listing Criteria for the US Endangered Species Act	CONSERVATION BIOLOGY			English	Article						Bayesian analysis; loss functions; performance testing; population viability analysis	UNCERTAINTY; ADVICE; MODELS	Lack of guidance for interpreting the definitions of endangered and threatened in the U.S. Endangered Species Act (ESA) has resulted in case-by-case decision making leaving the process vulnerable to being considered arbitrary or capricious. Adopting quantitative decision rules would remedy this but requires the agency to specify the relative urgency concerning extinction events over time, cutoff risk values corresponding to different levels of protection, and the importance given to different types of listing errors. We tested the performance of 3 sets of decision rules that use alternative functions for weighting the relative urgency of future extinction events: a threshold rule set, which uses a decision rule of x% probability of extinction over y years; a concave rule set, where the relative importance of future extinction events declines exponentially over time; and a shoulder rule set that uses a sigmoid shape function, where relative importance declines slowly at first and then more rapidly. We obtained decision cutoffs by interviewing several biologists and then emulated the listing process with simulations that covered a range of extinction risks typical of ESA listing decisions. We evaluated performance of the decision rules under different data quantities and qualities on the basis of the relative importance of misclassification errors. Although there was little difference between the performance of alternative decision rules for correct listings, the distribution of misclassifications differed depending on the function used. Misclassifications for the threshold and concave listing criteria resulted in more overprotection errors, particularly as uncertainty increased, whereas errors for the shoulder listing criteria were more symmetrical. We developed and tested the framework for quantitative decision rules for listing species under the U.S. ESA. If policy values can be agreed on, use of this framework would improve the implementation of the ESA by increasing transparency and consistency.	[Regan, Tracey J.] Univ Melbourne, Sch Bot, Parkville, Vic 3010, Australia; [Regan, Tracey J.; Taylor, Barbara L.] Natl Marine Fisheries Serv, SW Fisheries Sci Ctr, La Jolla, CA 92037 USA; [Thompson, Grant G.] NOAA, Resource Ecol & Fisheries Management Div, Alaska Fisheries Sci Ctr, Natl Marine Fisheries Serv, Seattle, WA 98115 USA; [Cochrane, Jean Fitts] US Fish & Wildlife Serv, Endangered Species Program, Arlington, VA 22203 USA; [Ralls, Katherine] Smithsonian Inst, Natl Zool Pk, Smithsonian Conservat Biol Inst, Washington, DC 20008 USA; [Runge, Michael C.] US Geol Survey, Patuxent Wildlife Res Ctr, Laurel, MD 20708 USA; [Merrick, Richard] Natl Marine Fisheries Serv, Off Assistant Administrator, Silver Spring, MD 20910 USA	Regan, TJ (reprint author), Univ Melbourne, Sch Bot, Parkville, Vic 3010, Australia.	tregan@unimelb.edu.au	Runge, Michael/E-7331-2011	Runge, Michael/0000-0002-8081-536X	National Marine Fisheries Service; U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service; National Research Council; Australian Research Council Centre of Excellence for Environmental Decisions	T.J.R. was jointly funded by the National Marine Fisheries Service and the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service through a fellowship with the National Research Council and the Australian Research Council Centre of Excellence for Environmental Decisions. We thank L. Maguire, M. Nammack, T. Ragen, and S. Rumsey for expert advice; and A. Read, P. Boveng, P. Wade, and M. Burgman for their useful comments. We honour the passing of Dr. Dan Goodman who provided software and intellectual stimulation for this project. Dan devoted much of his career to integrating decision theory into conservation biology and his mentoring was very important to several authors of this work.		34	13	13	0	48	WILEY-BLACKWELL	HOBOKEN	111 RIVER ST, HOBOKEN 07030-5774, NJ USA	0888-8892			CONSERV BIOL	Conserv. Biol.	AUG	2013	27	4					821	831		10.1111/cobi.12055				11	Biodiversity Conservation; Ecology; Environmental Sciences	Biodiversity & Conservation; Environmental Sciences & Ecology	185PB	WOS:000321980800019	23646933				2018-10-25	J	Synes, NW; Osborne, PE				Synes, Nicholas W.; Osborne, Patrick E.			Choice of predictor variables as a source of uncertainty in continental-scale species distribution modelling under climate change	GLOBAL ECOLOGY AND BIOGEOGRAPHY			English	Article						Bioclimatic variables; climate change; equifinality; Europe; map comparison techniques; predictor variables; species distribution models; uncertainty	ENVELOPE MODELS; POTENTIAL IMPACTS; PERFORMANCE; CHALLENGES; RESOLUTION; SURFACES; IMPROVE; ABSENCE; BIRDS	Aim Species distribution modelling is commonly used to guide future conservation policies in the light of potential climate change. However, arbitrary decisions during the model-building process can affect predictions and contribute to uncertainty about where suitable climate space will exist. For many species, the key climatic factors limiting distributions are unknown. This paper assesses the uncertainty generated by using different climate predictor variable sets for modelling the impacts of climate change. Location Europe, 10 degrees W to 50 degrees E and 30 degrees N to 60 degrees N. Methods Using 1453 presence pixels at 30 arcsec resolution for the great bustard (Otis tarda), predictions of future distribution were made based on two emissions scenarios, three general climate models and 26 sets of predictor variables. Twenty-six current models were created, and 156 for both 2050 and 2080. Map comparison techniques were used to compare predictions in terms of the quantity and the location of presences (map comparison kappa, MCK) and using a range change index (RCI). Generalized linear models (GLMs) were used to partition explained deviance in MCK and RCI among sources of uncertainty. Results The 26 different variable sets achieved high values of AUC (area under the receiver operating characteristic curve) and yet introduced substantial variation into maps of current distribution. Differences between maps were even greater when distributions were projected into the future. Some 64-78% of the variation between future maps was attributable to choice of predictor variable set alone. Choice of general climate model and emissions scenario contributed a maximum of 15% variation and their order of importance differed for MCK and RCI. Main conclusions Generalized variable sets produce an unmanageable level of uncertainty in species distribution models which cannot be ignored. The use of sound ecological theory and statistical methods to check predictor variables can reduce this uncertainty, but our knowledge of species may be too limited to make more than arbitrary choices. When all sources of modelling uncertainty are considered together, it is doubtful whether ensemble methods offer an adequate solution. Future studies should explicitly acknowledge uncertainty due to arbitrary choices in the model-building process and develop ways to convey the results to decision-makers.	[Synes, Nicholas W.; Osborne, Patrick E.] Univ Southampton, Fac Engn & Environm, Ctr Environm Sci, Southampton SO17 1BJ, Hants, England	Osborne, PE (reprint author), Univ Southampton, Fac Engn & Environm, Ctr Environm Sci, Southampton SO17 1BJ, Hants, England.	p.e.osborne@soton.ac.uk		Synes, Nicholas/0000-0001-8114-8944	BirdLife International; CMS; Lebensministerium of Austria	This study used data gathered for the BustardMap project. Thanks are due to: Lara Salido Grana, Pedro J. Leitao, Szabolcs Nagy, Rainer Raab, Eike Julius, Vlasta Skorpikova, Jitka Uhlikova, the Hungarian OTIS-LIFE Project and data held by the Monitoring Centre at the University of West Hungary, Institute of Wildlife Management, Kiskunsag National Park Directorate, Sandor Floris Kalmar, Pedro Rocha, Susana Suarez Seoane, Manuel Morales, Eduardo de Juana, Nuri Ozbagdatli, Yuri Andryushchenko, Alexander Antonchikov, Astrid Eisenberg, Norbert Eschholz, Thomas Bich and Torsten Langgemach. The BustardMap project was funded by BirdLife International, CMS and the Lebensministerium of Austria. Four referees and two editors provided valuable comments on the manuscript and excellent suggestions for future studies.		55	94	95	1	65	WILEY-BLACKWELL	MALDEN	COMMERCE PLACE, 350 MAIN ST, MALDEN 02148, MA USA	1466-822X			GLOBAL ECOL BIOGEOGR	Glob. Ecol. Biogeogr.	NOV	2011	20	6					904	914		10.1111/j.1466-8238.2010.00635.x				11	Ecology; Geography, Physical	Environmental Sciences & Ecology; Physical Geography	836UD	WOS:000296137400010					2018-10-25	J	Loehle, C				Loehle, Craig			Criteria for assessing climate change impacts on ecosystems	ECOLOGY AND EVOLUTION			English	Article						Biodiversity; climate envelope model; extinction risk; General Circulation Model; impact assessment	ELEVATED CO2; SPECIES DISTRIBUTIONS; PACIFIC-NORTHWEST; GLOBAL CHANGE; LAND-USE; MODELS; FOREST; VEGETATION; CHALLENGES; RESPONSES	There is concern about the potential impacts of climate change on species and ecosystems. To address this concern, a large body of literature has developed in which these impacts are assessed. In this study, criteria for conducting reliable and useful assessments of impacts of future climate are suggested. The major decisions involve: clearly defining an emissions scenario; selecting a climate model; evaluating climate model skill and bias; quantifying General Circulation Model (GCM) between-model variability; selecting an ecosystem model and assessing uncertainty; properly considering transient versus equilibrium responses; including effects of CO2 on plant response; evaluating implications of simplifying assumptions; and considering animal linkage with vegetation. A sample of the literature was surveyed in light of these criteria. Many of the studies used climate simulations that were >10 years old and not representative of best current models. Future effects of elevated CO2 on plant drought resistance and productivity were generally included in growth model studies but not in niche (habitat suitability) studies, causing the latter to forecast greater future adverse impacts. Overly simplified spatial representation was frequent and caused the existence of refugia to be underestimated. Few studies compared multiple climate simulations and ecosystem models (including parametric uncertainty), leading to a false impression of precision and potentially arbitrary results due to high between-model variance. No study assessed climate model retrodictive skill or bias. Overall, most current studies fail to meet all of the proposed criteria. Suggestions for improving assessments are provided.	Natl Council Air & Stream Improvement Inc, Naperville, IL 60540 USA	Loehle, C (reprint author), Natl Council Air & Stream Improvement Inc, 552 S Washington St,Suite 224, Naperville, IL 60540 USA.	CLoehle@ncasi.org						67	9	10	0	22	WILEY-BLACKWELL	HOBOKEN	111 RIVER ST, HOBOKEN 07030-5774, NJ USA	2045-7758			ECOL EVOL	Ecol. Evol.	SEP	2011	1	1					63	72		10.1002/ece3.7				10	Ecology; Evolutionary Biology	Environmental Sciences & Ecology; Evolutionary Biology	055TE	WOS:000312439700007	22393483	DOAJ Gold, Green Published			2018-10-25	J	Dormann, CF; Purschke, O; Marquez, JRG; Lautenbach, S; Schroder, B				Dormann, Carsten F.; Purschke, Oliver; Marquez, Jaime R. Garcia; Lautenbach, Sven; Schroeder, Boris			COMPONENTS OF UNCERTAINTY IN SPECIES DISTRIBUTION ANALYSIS: A CASE STUDY OF THE GREAT GREY SHRIKE	ECOLOGY			English	Article						artificial neural network; best subset regression; climate change; collinearity; data uncertainty; Generalized Additive Models, GAM; Generalized Linear Models, GLM; prediction; Saxony, Germany; sequential regression; species distribution model; stepwise model selection	DISTRIBUTION MODELS; CLIMATE-CHANGE; HABITAT MODELS; GLOBAL CHANGE; CONSERVATION BIOLOGY; MULTIPLE-REGRESSION; SPATIAL PREDICTION; ECOLOGICAL THEORY; RANGE SHIFTS; FUTURE	Sophisticated statistical analyses are common in ecological research, particularly in species distribution modeling. The effects of sometimes arbitrary decisions during the modeling procedure on the final outcome are difficult to assess, and to date are largely unexplored. We conducted an analysis quantifying the contribution of uncertainty in each step during the model-building sequence to variation in model validity and climate change projection uncertainty. Our study system was the distribution of the Great Grey Shrike in the German federal state of Saxony. For each of four steps (data quality, collinearity method, model type, and variable selection), we ran three different options in a factorial experiment, leading to 81 different model approaches. Each was subjected to a fivefold cross-validation, measuring area under curve (AUC) to assess model quality. Next, we used three climate change scenarios times three precipitation realizations to project future distributions from each model, yielding 729 projections. Again, we analyzed which step introduced most variability (the four model-building steps plus the two scenario steps) into predicted species prevalences by the year 2050. Predicted prevalences ranged from a factor of 0.2 to a factor of 10 of present prevalence, with the majority of predictions between 1.1 and 4.2 (inter-quartile range). We found that model type and data quality dominated this analysis. In particular, artificial neural networks yielded low cross-validation robustness and gave very conservative climate change predictions. Generalized linear and additive models were very similar in quality and predictions, and superior to neural networks. Variations in scenarios and realizations had very little effect, due to the small spatial extent of the study region and its relatively small range of climatic conditions. We conclude that, for climate projections, model type and data quality were the most influential factors. Since comparison of model types has received good coverage in the ecological literature, effects of data quality should now come under more scrutiny.	[Dormann, Carsten F.; Purschke, Oliver; Marquez, Jaime R. Garcia; Lautenbach, Sven] UFZ Helmholtz Ctr Environm Res, Dept Computat Landscape Ecol, D-04318 Leipzig, Germany; [Purschke, Oliver] Lund Univ, Dept Phys Geog & Ecosyst Anal, GeoBiosphere Sci Ctr, S-22362 Lund, Sweden; [Marquez, Jaime R. Garcia] Univ Bonn, Nees Inst Plant Biodivers, D-53115 Bonn, Germany; [Schroeder, Boris] Univ Potsdam, Inst Geoecol, D-14476 Potsdam, Germany	Dormann, CF (reprint author), UFZ Helmholtz Ctr Environm Res, Dept Computat Landscape Ecol, Permoserstr 15, D-04318 Leipzig, Germany.	carsten.dormann@ufz.de	Lautenbach, Sven/C-1235-2010; Schroder, Boris/B-7211-2009	Lautenbach, Sven/0000-0003-1825-9996; Schroder, Boris/0000-0002-8577-7980; Dormann, Carsten/0000-0002-9835-1794				87	102	104	2	53	WILEY-BLACKWELL	HOBOKEN	111 RIVER ST, HOBOKEN 07030-5774, NJ USA	0012-9658	1939-9170		ECOLOGY	Ecology	DEC	2008	89	12					3371	3386		10.1890/07-1772.1				16	Ecology	Environmental Sciences & Ecology	381GP	WOS:000261524000013	19137944				2018-10-25	J	Sutherst, RW; Maywald, G				Sutherst, RW; Maywald, G			A climate model of the red imported fire ant, Solenopsis invicta Buren (Hymenoptera : Formicidae): Implications for invasion of new regions, particularly Oceania	ENVIRONMENTAL ENTOMOLOGY			English	Article						CLIMEX; species mapping; invasion; biogeography; climate	RANGE EXPANSION; SPECIES DISTRIBUTIONS; COLONY-GROWTH; NORTH-AMERICA; GLOBAL CHANGE; HYBRID ZONE; GYPSY-MOTH; FRUIT-FLY; POPULATION; SURVIVAL	The paucity of empirical data on processes in species life cycles demands tools to extract insight from field observations. Such insights help inform policy on invasive species and on impacts of climate change at regional and local scales. We used the CLIMEX model to infer the response of the red imported fire ant, Solenopsis invicta Buren (Hymenoptera: Formicidae), to temperature and moisture from its range in the United States. We tested hypotheses on the mechanisms that limit the distribution of the ant and estimated the potential global area at risk from invasion. The ant can spread further in the United States, including north along the west coast, where patterns of infestation will differ from those in the east. We analyzed the risk of colonization in Australia and New Zealand, where the ant was recently discovered. The patterns of infestation of the ant in Oceania will differ from those in the eastern United States, with slower growth and less winter mortality. This study adds to earlier temperature-based models by incorporating a moisture response; by replacing arbitrary categories of colony size to predict overwintering success with a site-specific model based on the balance between annual growth and survival; and by comparing different hypotheses on low temperature-related mechanisms that limit the geographical distribution. It shows how the response of a species to climate can be synthesized from field observations to provide useful insights into its population dynamics. Such analyses provide a basis for making decisions on regional management of invasive species and an informative context for local studies.	CSIRO Entomol, Long Pocket Labs, Indooroopilly, Qld 4068, Australia	Sutherst, RW (reprint author), CSIRO Entomol, Long Pocket Labs, 120 Meiers Rd, Indooroopilly, Qld 4068, Australia.	bob.sutherst@csiro.au						66	93	114	2	50	ENTOMOL SOC AMER	LANHAM	9301 ANNAPOLIS RD, LANHAM, MD 20706 USA	0046-225X			ENVIRON ENTOMOL	Environ. Entomol.	APR	2005	34	2					317	335		10.1603/0046-225X-34.2.317				19	Entomology	Entomology	914XS	WOS:000228262000011					2018-10-25	